✓ zhenwu@cs.stonybrook.edu • website

Zhengyu Wu



ABOUT ME

I am a second-year Computer Science Ph.D Student at Stony Brook University. I work in the NetSys Lab with my advisor, Aruna Balasubramanian. My research interests include network performance, mainly peer-to-peer networks and decentralized distributed storage systems.

EDUCATION

Ph.D Student in Computer Science

Stony Brook University, New York, USA

Jan 2022 - Present GPA: 3.93/4.0

Advisor: Prof. Aruna Balasubramanian

B.S. Computer Science

Stony Brook University, New York, USA

Aug 2017 - May 2021

Publication

Is IPFS Ready for Decentralized Video Streaming?

WWW2023

GPA: 3.80/4.0

ChengHao Ryan Yang, Zhengyu Wu, Santiago Vargas, and Aruna Balasubramanian.

• The video playback experience on IPFS suffers from network instability and static video quality. Traditional ABR streaming performs poorly due to inaccurate network estimation. The proposed IPFS-aware algorithm, called Telescope, can update ABR's estimation on the fly and significantly improve the video playback experience.

Work Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Fall 2021 - Fall 2022

Stony Brook University

New York

- Graduate teaching assistant for Introduction to Network Administration. Introduced students with hands-on experience on fundamentals of network management, such as TCP/IP networking protocols, hardware, architecture, media, and
- Graduate teaching assistant for Computer Networks. Helped students learn the fundamental structure of the Internet.

Web/Database Support

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Stony Brook University

New York

• Maintained the Computer Science Department's websites at Stony Brook University by using Drupal, a widely used content management system (CMS), and MySQL.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Spring 2019, Fall 2019

Stony Brook University

New York

- Undergraduate teaching assistant for Computer Science I. Helped students learn the fundamentals of objective programming.
- Undergraduate teaching assistant for Fundamentals of Software Development. Introduced students to systematic design, development and testing of software systems.

Jun 2018 - Present Founder New York

Hoshiro Entertainment

• Founded a company services translating games from Japanese to English and Chinese.

• Successfully maintained a group of over 10 translators and helped partners reach over a million dollar in sales.

SKILLS

Python, Go, Java, C, Git, LATEX, MarkDown **Programming**

Communication Chinese (native), English (business), Japanese (conversational)